It's time.
Water, check.
Cup of coffee, check.
Insatiable addiction, check.
Are you ready?
We're about to kick things off.
Wait, what day is it today?
It's Sunday, right?
Hey, it's Easter today.
Happy Easter, everybody.
Yeah.
What's going on?
Can't believe you guys are here watching me on Easter day.
I mean, obviously, I was going to play this game on Easter.
What else am I going to do?
Go out there and find eggs or something?
Come on, now.
I'm going to play Isaac.
That is my Easter.
What is Oliver actually about?
I don't know.
I kind of hate my name, actually.
Like the YouTube name.
I would rather be called Oliver David, but someone took the nick already, unfortunately.
I hate about Oliver.
It sucks.
The problem is it's so ingrained in everything, you know?
There's links to... I don't know, man.
What about Oliver?
That name was taken, which is not surprising.
Who's David?
That's my middle name.
I like it.
It's like Larry David, you know?
But I'm Oliver David.
He's the comedian.
I'm the YouTuber.
I don't know.
I think it sounds good.
I always liked the name Larry David, so I was like Oliver David.
That sounds pretty good.
I love Larry David.
You're still playing this awful game.
How dare you?
This game is really fun.
But then again, that's fair.
I mean, it's not for everybody, I guess.
I'm honestly surprised that I'm still having as much fun as I do with this game, considering that it should be on paper, be a game that I hate.
Since it's so full of bullets everywhere, it's not really my cup of tea.
But somehow, it still is super fun.
Like, just the progression aspect of this game is very addicting.
That's what's keeping me going right now.
Unlocking new items, finding new characters, getting that dopamine hit when you get far and a great combination of items.
It's really fun.
It is.
What's your plan for today?
I'm going to play this game for approximately three hours or so, because I've got to go around six o'clock tonight.
Maybe I can stretch it to three hours and thirty.
And then I'm going to go for a long walk.
And then I'm going to eat.
I've started walking ten thousand steps a day.
It's part of my thing now.
It's actually quite nice, except I found out that... what's it called?
I have shitty shoes.
Like, I can't walk more than approximately seven kilometers without my heels hurting.
So I need to go get that taken care of somehow.
Maybe get some better shoes, maybe some some things you can put inside the shoe to make it more comfortable, you know?
But yeah.
Do you listen to something on the walks?
I do!
I've been listening to a lot of podcasts lately.
I do love Dworkish.
I think his name was Patel on YouTube.
He has a lot of people on talking about AI and stuff, you know?
It's a lot of fun.
I've been watching the one with Dario Asmodeus.
I think his name is the CEO of Anthropic.
That was a really interesting one.
It's just cool to know all these things that I didn't know much about, you know?
It's really insightful.
Why is Twitch censoring Azazel?
It's not!
I can see you writing it.
It's not being censored.
What are you guys's plans today on Easter?
Are you eating something special or... I know that if you're in Italy you're making all kinds of weird cakes, right?
The Easter lunch or whatever?
We don't really do much of that here.
I guess it is a thing that we make like egg chase or egg hunts and stuff, but not me.
I'm just here with my cat, Jackie.
Preparing for midterm?
Well, there you go.
Why are you here?
Get out of here, Aryan fools!
Go prepare for your midterm.
Don't listen to me.
I'm just gonna be distracted.
We have a cake cake in the shape of a lamb?
Okay, that's cool.
For some reason I was reminded of that sketch with... Can we have a line in the shape of a balloon or in the shape of a kitty or something?
You know that one on YouTube.
When are you playing a new game?
After Silksong, I'm gonna play a new game.
It's gonna be recorded on YouTube.
You'll find out what it is.
After this game, I'm gonna play a new game.
I don't know when I'm gonna be done playing this, when I don't have fun anymore.
And I don't know when that'll be.
Maybe soon?
Maybe after today?
Maybe in a year?
Nobody knows.
I can't predict the future on that.
Oh yeah, right.
I haven't reached act 20 of Silksong yet.
You're right.
Damn.
It's gonna take a while.
Whoo!
Man, that... those 20 bucks, huh?
Well, for me, 60 bucks.
Really well spent.
Supposed to be working on the civil engineering thesis.
But instead, I'm sitting here watching Oliver.
There's nothing you can do about it.
I can... I can talk to you about that.
That's what I can do about it.
I can tell you you should be working on your civil engineering thesis.
Don't listen to me.
Go, go, go.
You can watch the VOD.
Besides, in the VOD, you're gonna get 4k resolution.
Huh?
Go for the VOD!
VOD people know what they're doing, you know?
They're smart.
You guys are also smart.
We're all smart here.
You gotta at least unlock all the characters in Isaac.
You don't gotta tell me what I gotta do.
I'll unlock exactly as many characters as I want.
Maybe I'll even lock characters again after unlocking them, just to make you mad.
Because that's apparently what I do, you know?
I induce rage in people.
I bait out the rage.
And I'm apparently very good at it.
I should really get into some kind of rage bait profession.
How many characters would you guess there is?
I don't know.
Maybe... how many do I have now?
Maybe 10?
Maybe 20?
That's my guess.
Don't, don't tell me.
I'm just thinking out loud, right?
Alright guys, I'm going in.
Wish me luck.
Hold on.
Let me do this.
You guys actually can see it.
Oh wait, you can't see it.
You can't see it!
Now you can see it.
Move this over.
There we go.
And now we gotta change the music thingy.
There we are.
Something I'm really excited about is this little preview here on file 1.
It looks to me like some kind of frame that's in there.
And it looks to me like there's a flower on the right and some kind of creature in the bottom left.
But the thing is, we're gonna find more pieces of this.
And what's that gonna mean?
What's it mean?
We'll find out.
Oh yeah, I'm in the middle of a run apparently.
I'm four seconds into a run.
Let's continue that one.
Not really sure what I was doing.
Uh, it's a new character.
Yeah, and we have a box of friends.
Creates a duplicate of each of Isaac's familiars for the current room.
If Isaac has no familiars to duplicate, grants one demon baby familiar for the room instead.
Aha!
And we have one red heart, two black hearts.
Wait, we have a demon baby now though?
I didn't use my box.
Weird.
Wait!
I shoot from the baby!
Oh, that's gonna mess me up guys.
It's already over.
How on earth am I gonna deal with that?
That sounds ridiculous.
I don't want to step in there.
Oh god.
I need to train my eyes to look differently now.
Oh no, I lost some HP already.
It's not good.
So if I use my item now, I should have two of these, right?
Wait, are they all gonna be shooting them?
Oh, hold on now.
That sounds pretty damn good, if that's the case.
Get this guy out of the way.
Uh, sir, will you just die please?
There we go.
Thank you.
Now, this guy up here is gonna be a nuisance because he's doing the horizontal ones and they are very annoying.
Like, how am I gonna deal with this?
This is super awkward.
How does anyone play this character?
Oh, you know what?
They both shoot!
Fuck yeah!
Oh no, I died or I'm...
Everyone else died, but I lost my HP.
Shit.
Okay, that's actually kind of dope.
I need to find familiar stats.
Now, do I go inside the boss room?
I think I do!
I'm going crazy.
Larry Jr. Easy.
Even with this handicap that I have here.
Okay.
Why is he just going like that?
Not bad, not bad.
He be pooping.
Would be awesome if my baby could sort of throw attention as well.
Make them attack the baby instead.
Oh, I split it in two.
Uh, sir, come here.
Yeah!
PJs!
He was all red hearts.
Plus four soul hearts!
Guys, you know what we need now, right?
That's right.
We need a converter.
We need it right now.
I'm also poor, so I can't do anything about that.
Converter is the best active in the game.
And I'm gonna be praying for the inverter every time now.
Kill this guy.
Oh, I mean, so far it's not that bad.
It's okay.
We're kind of crushing it.
Then again, it is the first floor.
Very nice.
That looks like some kind of baby.
Robo baby!
Friends till the bzzt!
Familiar that fires lasers.
They both shooting!
Okay, this character is kind of dope.
I think I like it a lot.
Huge fan.
And wait, if I use my active now...
Oh boy!
We're gonna have four babies!
600 babies!
Oh man, I don't know why I've been thinking about that meme so much lately.
Come here.
Alright, go.
Wish me luck.
I have not given up on trying to understand the timer, but I have given up for now.
We're gonna think about it more later.
Right now, I just want to... I just want to glide, you know?
Dude, this is sick as hell!
Wait, the laser goes through obstacles.
Oh, it's super hard to aim though.
Okay.
Let's see here.
Scan the rocks.
Clear.
Nothing for me here.
I wonder if I can somehow pick these up with my familiars.
I don't think so.
Oh, Jesus.
Nice.
What's this?
A box of spiders!
Oh no, it's an active!
Boo!
Oh, you know what actually?
We're gonna do this.
And then switch.
Optimization, people.
It's important.
Unfortunately, my spiders are not shooting projectiles.
Or tiles.
Honestly, it's gonna be me shooting in the dark.
Mostly, because I can't keep track of where my babies are.
Oh, it's gonna be easy with this one.
Look.
No problem.
Nice.
Oh,
beautiful.
Okay, so wait a minute.
This one is easy.
Nice.
Now we take care of this guy.
Give me that.
Good.
Oh, this guy.
So we go up here.
Come on, come on.
Why are you not hitting them?
Okay, well, that works.
I think we should check out the shop at least.
Ah, one key left?
That may not be worth it.
Let's just keep exploring.
TNT!
Bait them over.
Okay, okay, that works.
Come here.
Good.
That works.
Look for tinted rocks.
I don't see them.
I could go in here.
I am gonna do it.
Oh, they're invisible.
Kill them.
Oh, fuck!
Oh, my god!
Jesus!
Okay, we got them.
Yeah, pills!
Fuck!
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
Does that even affect me?
Hold on a minute.
Those shot speeds or cheers even affect me, because I feel like that's the same that I had before.
It's the same.
Very nice.
I don't think it affects my babies.
It affects me, but I don't care about me.
It's all about my babies.
Why am I here?
Oh, there's a button, I see.
Will you please hit the thing?
Okay.
Sometimes it doesn't look like...
Or it looks like it's gonna hit, but then it doesn't, you know?
Oh, hey, we go!
Nice!
Then we got this one over here.
Playing a mega save.
And here.
Okay.
Not bad.
That's the stuff I can allow myself to do when I have lasers like that.
Now, can I make my babies run through this instead?
No.
That would be cool though, wouldn't it?
Time to leave.
I've yet to use my box, by the way.
I think I should use it more.
Just more liberally, you know?
I guess I keep with this... I keep thinking that I'm gonna save it for a rainy day and all that, but most days here are rainy.
Okay, so we can't afford that.
You know what?
Here's the plan.
I am going to donate all my money.
It's time we filled this old machine up.
Yeah, that's what I'll say.
That is like one of the main objectives of this run today here.
Is to fill up the machine.
Let's have multiple babies!
Oh my god, how do I avoid that?
Fuck me!
Okay, okay.
This is gonna be interesting.
How am I gonna do this?
Ah, this is awkward as hell.
I guess I can sort of follow him.
It's not pretty, but it works.
This is really awkward with the babies.
Pretty good though.
Spawn seven random coins and one random...
What's that coin?
Butt penny!
Isaac farts when picking up coins.
Destroyed poops are 20% more likely to drop coins.
Hey!
Oh, it even pushes objects away.
That's funny.
I think I'm gonna go in here.
Maybe make a deal.
Wait, missing page two.
Extra black heart deals room-wide damage upon taking a hit that reduces Isaac's...
Isaac to one heart remaining.
What is this?
Death's list.
We gain demon stat but lost angel stat.
Upon entering each room, a skull mark appears over a random enemy.
Killing that enemy first moves the mark to another enemy.
If all enemies are killed in the order of the mark, Isaac is rewarded with a...
pickup or a small permanent stat boost!
That sounds awesome!
Killing an enemy in the wrong order causes the mark to disappear and the bonus...
reward to be lost.
Yo!
That's gonna be tough to do with...
these babies.
I'm just saying this is gonna be really tough.
Because I have no control over where they go, at least very limited.
Yeah.
Also, why did my red heart get consumed?
Sometimes I feel like it consumes blue hearts first and then red hearts.
It's a little bit confusing.
Let's just move on.
Okay, I'm curious to see this mark system.
I did not hit her.
I did not.
Oh, hi mark.
Oh wait, there's no mark!
I fucked it up already.
Yeah, I don't see a mark.
Man, the damage is not that great, is it?
I see the mark!
It's gonna fuck me over, isn't it?
Did
I kill him?
I think I messed it up.
I think I'm not gonna focus on the marks.
It's gonna kill me if I do it.
Man, the more I play like this, the more I hate the baby system.
I can't fucking aim like this.
It's terrible.
Just the delay... Oh, you know what I need?
I need that item that locks the enemies or my familiars onto my character.
Holy shit!
Imagine that item.
That'll be dope as hell.
Okay, we're actually killing them in the order.
Yeah, yeah?
Oh, please kill him.
It is so difficult!
This is gonna be a short run.
I'm gonna donate all my money for sure.
Okay, definitely duplicating here, man.
Kill something.
Babies!
Kill him!
Oh my god.
Shoot!
Can we get the white babies up here too?
There we go.
Okay.
No!
Horrible.
Man, I'm full of gas today.
Ooh, okay.
Love me some pills.
Paramones?
That one, I don't remember what does.
Let's see if we can find the mark.
There you are.
Oh, this is gonna be tough because he's gonna move around all the time.
There's no way.
There's no way to do this.
Yeah, just kill him.
Or we damage them enough so that it only requires a couple hits on every one of them.
I killed something there.
Where are you?
This is gonna take forever.
Nice.
What's that?
Wait, did I actually kill them in the right order?
Increases the chance of lock-based shots to be fired?
Oh, wait, do I want that instead of the butt penny?
Wait, do I have any lock-based shots?
I don't.
But I could have later, right?
Let me equip this for now and then come back and change it if I find something that makes me shoot lock-based shots.
Yeah, let's go in here.
I'm gonna consume my thingy and let's go nuts.
Fuck, I'm an idiot.
Well, that was not very smart.
There we go.
I thought it was a new one.
Bro, this is actually impossible with the babies!
You can't consistently hit the same targets.
Get it, get it!
Okay, there we go, there we go.
This is just shooting in a random direction and hoping something hits.
This is the strategy here.
And you know what?
It's not a bad strategy.
It's actually okay.
We can blow that up.
What if I were to shoot this?
Yeah, fart it up.
Come on.
Got him.
Good enough.
That was my only key?
Wow.
Oh, we got to kill them in the order.
We can just totally do this.
Oh no, not if these guys spawn.
Ah, never mind, it's over.
Oh my god.
Nice.
So we have a boss here.
Uh, only one heart left.
This is not looking good.
I want to find a shop and donate before I die.
This is the plan.
Hey, we can totally get across here.
Oh my goodness, very nice.
The hermit, okay.
Oh my god, we got more.
Fuck!
Oh man.
Okay, well we got more batteries if we need.
What's that?
The spin to win.
Oh, that one sucks so bad.
I hate it.
It's also an active, so boo.
Here we go, shop.
Okay, I have 15.
I can get a mom's box.
Guess mother plus one luck spawns a trinket.
Doubles the effects of trinkets.
Um, or I get a heart.
Oh, I'm honestly tempted to buy heart instead.
Here's what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna buy this, I'm gonna buy that, and I'm gonna donate the rest.
There we go.
Doink.
Donate.
180, baby.
180.
Uh, let's see here.
The pill.
Retro.
Nah, okay.
Uh, I'm just gonna go in here, fuck it.
I have no fear.
Kill him!
We can definitely do this in the right order.
No!
Fuck!
Oh my god!
Let's shoot him down!
We got him.
Oh, we gotta go for the fire now?
Oh, it's the tomato, I see.
I couldn't even see that was a tomato from, uh...
What do you call it?
From the retrovision.
Yeah!
We gotta stand up from that?
Did I understand that correctly?
That's sick!
Whoa!
Holy moly!
Also, I totally should have used my active there, because I had so many batteries.
That was a misplay for sure.
But, okay, so here's the thing.
Do I pick this up?
I think I do.
I feel like I'm not finding that many, uh, poops.
I'm gonna bet on finding some kind of item that will give me a random chance on attack.
Yeah.
That sounds good.
It's Gertie!
Wait!
Gertie Senior!
This is massive!
Kill the little fly first?
Yo, we actually killed him in the right order!
Don't kill the tomato!
Oh, I killed the fly!
Too bad.
Well, in that case, we killed the tomato.
Alright, this is going pretty swell.
Yeah, not bad.
The stapler.
More damage.
Stables my eyeshot, but that doesn't affect me at all.
I'm chilling with that.
And we're gonna get an extra heart, because I kept the the white heart.
Things are looking up here.
Okay.
Empty room.
Let's see if we can't kill this in the right order.
It's gonna be tough against these enemies, though.
Shit!
Come on!
Kill him!
It is so difficult to do!
Hit him!
Yes!
No, I killed the wrong enemy.
Damn!
It is so hard to utilize this item with these babies.
It's unreal.
Yeah, this ain't happening.
Trying to kill these guys in the right order.
Good luck.
I kind of like this setup.
Just standing here and shooting lasers.
It's safe.
And it's solid.
That's getting closer.
There we go.
Nice.
No reward.
It's too bad.
Man, it would be so fun to try this item, where you mark the enemies, when you don't have this character.
I would love to try that.
I could get in there.
Yeah, it's worth it.
Nice.
This could be a spiked box.
Thank god it's not.
Have I gotten my treasure yet?
No, I haven't.
Oh, shit!
Wow!
Damn.
No way, I can't get to that pill.
Well, that's great.
Fantastic.
Come on, line them up, line them up.
Line them up.
Oh, this is easy.
There's only one enemy.
Or is there?
I think I may have messed it up.
Because it splits, right?
And then it's all over.
And now I see a bunch of poop, right after I exchange my trinket here.
Unfortunate.
Wait a minute, how come I didn't get an extra heart?
Didn't I have a white heart?
Oh, maybe I didn't have any hearts at all, actually.
I see how it is.
The Hierophant.
Oh, very much needed.
Thank you.
That's gonna come in handy.
I still haven't found the treasure room, though, so I'm not gonna engage yet.
I don't remember the map layout, but I think I haven't been here yet.
We're gonna try and kill them in the right order.
Good, good.
Yes!
Yeah, there we go, look!
Oh, well, it cost us a heart to do, but you know, it was fun.
That probably wasn't worth it.
It was totally worth it!
What the fuck, man!
Super duper worth!
Where's the treasure room?
Uh, okay, so wait, where have I been?
Is this the wrong way?
Okay, here we go.
Man, kill it, please!
Okay, I could go in here.
I'm gonna go in here.
Ah, man!
That was totally not worth it!
Wow, what a shitty room!
I got fucked in the ass just now.
How are you supposed to dodge this?
Insanity!
I hesitated.
Yeah, good.
Wait, I messed it up?
I killed it in the wrong order?
How?
I thought that was perfect.
Uh, yeah, not happening.
Wait, uh, oh, I didn't mean to go here.
Just kill him, just kill him!
Please!
At least we found the treasure room.
That's something.
Is that a baby?
Acid baby!
Pills!
Oh, what's that?
Following Familia that drops a pill?
Every seven rooms!
Yeah!
Consuming a pill triggers acid baby to instantly damage all enemies in the current room and poison them.
That is a baby after my own heart.
Love it.
In fact, no, I'm not gonna bomb that.
I have one bomb left.
Come on.
I'm not doing that.
It's time for the boss.
Uh, if I can remember where it is.
I think it's over here.
Uh, this way?
No, this way.
I think.
We're definitely using the box.
This is gonna be crazy though.
We're gonna have so many babies.
Mega... Oh, it's gonna be tough to dodge this.
Wow, wow, wow.
Oh my god.
No!
God damn it.
Like, it is so hard for me to see where these...
or where my character is when there's like five characters that I have.
It's so difficult for me to do that.
Let's try this again.
This character's pretty cool.
Like, but I wish I could get the item that makes them stick to me, you know?
That would be cool.
Well, that's not a great start.
Fantastic start.
Couldn't have gone better.
Dude, wait, am I only gonna find familiars with this character?
I feel like that there can't be a...
this can't be a coincidence.
Familiar that consumes red heart pickups and drops black hearts, pills, cards, blue spiders or hostile spiders in return?
He wants to take your life.
I mean, that's pretty good, I guess.
Let's see how it goes.
Except he doesn't shoot.
That's very unfortunate.
So, oh no, I'm gonna try and keep track of the right one that shoots as well now.
I'm gonna leave the poop.
No, I'm gonna kill the poop.
Wow, that went really well.
Huge!
Love the pills.
I don't love that.
We could go to the boss now.
I don't mind.
Blighted ovum.
This freaking guy.
I still don't understand.
Whoops!
What the fuck is going on?
I'm dead, I'm dead.
I don't know where I am!
I can't with this character.
I can't see where my character is.
Please make like a circle around my character so I know where I am.
That pisses me off.
Let's get Judas!
Judas baby!
And look at this, we're immediately getting an item.
Monster manual.
Uh, yeah, why not?
But wait a minute, what was the standard item we had?
Temporary... oh, that is so good though.
Also, we have two out of three on Bookworm now.
I want to keep this one, I think.
Yeah.
Oh, it feels good to shoot from my own character again.
Holy shit.
That is a relief.
Give me that.
Okay.
Uh, no money.
I do have a bit of money.
We can take a look I guess.
Converter baby!
Okay, we gotta save up.
We gotta save up for that.
Oh yeah, oh yeah.
Definitely.
I can't believe it.
Fortune smiles upon us.
Oh, this guy's camouflaged as hell.
Fuck!
Dude, I keep trying to shoot with my baby.
I am totally that other character pilled right now.
I kept trying to shoot with my little familiar.
Jesus.
Also, why is my familiar moving opposite of me?
Huh?
I guess it's just the style of that familiar.
Very weird.
You gotta be kidding me.
I am at half an HP right now.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Get out!
Okay, man.
Fucking pushed me into the other guy.
Papa fly?
Turret follower.
Paint damage up?
No, that's another one.
Follows Isaac's movements on a delay.
Fires once per second with Isaac's tear damage.
I feel like I'm getting extremely unlucky with these first couple runs here.
Just give me the damage.
Damage is good.
Come here.
I'm forever gonna be cursed after that character because I keep looking at my familiar when I shoot.
It's gonna take a while to get used to here.
Number one thing we need to do on this character is find more HP.
That is the main thing.
Nice.
Good start, good start.
Give me that double damage.
Good.
Wait, how come the size of my tear changes?
Any suspicious rocks?
Nope.
Not in here.
This guy's on fire!
He walked inside the fire.
That's a cool interaction.
Let's have a look.
Man, I'm so freaking sad we had a converter on the last one.
I will never recover from that mentally.
That is such a tragedy.
Okay, it's famine.
Six.
Wow.
All right.
I keep looking at my fucking familiar.
Stop.
We're not doing that anymore.
Okay, okay.
Look at your character, motherfucker.
There we go.
Ball of bandages.
Okay, so this one... yeah, whatever.
It's gonna level up if I somehow find a million of the same item.
That's fine.
Maybe it happens.
It probably doesn't.
Okay, we got a hundred percent demon mode.
Come here.
Oh my god, he pooped on me!
I'm a magician.
Nice.
Very good.
Use all the items.
Yeah, the size of my tear goes up when I use this book.
Oh my god.
Man, it's rough with Judas.
It's really rough.
I need healing.
Drop your heart from me, please.
Please.
All right, I'll take a coin.
No suspicious rocks.
Not that it matters.
I have no bombs.
Nice.
Good stuff.
At least I'm not insta-dead now.
Did he just kill his own fly?
That's amazing.
Yeah, you like that?
I'm gonna throw more bombs.
No more bombs.
The world!
Oh, look at that.
That is wonderful.
Money and some keys.
Should we blow that guy up?
No, I'm gonna save it.
I'm gonna save this bomb.
There's a room I missed.
Uh-oh.
It's a crazy room.
Nice.
Any tinted rocks doesn't look like it.
No enemies?
Uh, down here, of course.
Is that a brass knuckle?
Tough love.
Two shots.
Chance to fire two shots that deal a lot of extra damage increases with the luck.
Okay, we gotta find luck.
Why is this TNT barrel different?
Aha!
Look at this!
I mean, not that it matters, because we revealed all the secrets.
But that's a huge discovery.
Very nice.
Uh, what the... what the what?
What the what now?
I keep looking at my... familiar.
Stop looking at him.
It's all about you now.
Not your babies.
Okay, there we go.
Uh, let's go for it.
No, wait, I have money.
It's time for the shop.
Okay, so what is this even?
I don't know.
I've never been able to buy it.
Ah, I'm really tempted.
I'm gonna do it.
Love that.
Donating some money.
The good news is we're never gonna fall for that pill again.
This run.
Now this boss is easy.
That's a relief at least.
Wait, how did he die so fast?
I actually don't know what just happened.
He was at half HP and then suddenly he died.
Magic eight ball.
Shot speed.
Chance of planetariums.
Yes, I would love to see a planetarium.
Two of spades.
We're gonna save that until we get a couple more keys.
Okay, okay, okay, so here we go.
Spiders are okay.
I keep looking at it.
It's insane.
I'm completely pilled on the familiar.
Wow.
Holy shit.
Oh, wow, wow, wow, wow.
I'm gonna die here.
It's actually over.
Wow.
Yes, massive, massive.
We need that HP.
So bad on this character.
That is changing everything.
We have a chance now guys.
Things are looking up.
We were down in the dirt but now we're in the heavens.
Oh yeah, we can do this.
Oh yeah, what you got?
What you got?
Oh wait, they're gonna extend.
Yeah,
beautiful, beautiful, beautiful.
Oh, oh, almost messed it up.
We need a bible.
Oh my god, we need a bible real bad.
Will you please die?
Okay, there
we go.
Hold on, I gotta sneeze.
Okay, let's do this.
No, that's unfair.
What have I come back to?
Great.
Love being drowsy.
That's good, I guess.
Oh, I'm really slow.
We're gonna wait a bit.
No way.
Oh, I can't even... Yes, I can!
Yes, I can!
Fuck yeah.
I'll come back for the rest later.
I'm even gonna go in here.
Oh my goodness, massive.
Actually, I'm gonna do this.
You never know if this will save me.
You gotta play it safe.
Especially when you have this many bombs.
Oh, boss time, huh?
Uh, yeah, why not?
Oh, fuck.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah, more health, baby!
Oh, this is looking up, this is looking up.
This is really nice.
I gotta get more items.
Actually, I can duplicate my keys now if I wanted, but let's wait and see if I can get more.
Oh, fuck you.
Not bad.
Get rid of the spider.
This is the first really good Judas run I've had.
So far, at least.
Ah, look at this!
What's that?
The sun!
Oh, that's a good one.
I think I'm definitely multiplying my keys in a second here.
Just in case I get another one, I'm gonna wait.
Oh, my god.
Good.
Oh, my god!
These enemies are actually super annoying!
I gotta do it!
Puberty.
That's pretty good, I guess.
Donate.
Grab that.
I should have multiplied before I entered.
Fuck.
Fuck it too.
Just do it.
We're moving on.
It is what it is.
Mistakes were made.
We're gonna live with them.
Get me out of here.
Take me to the next floor.
Unfortunately, doors closed.
So, there will be none of that.
Ow, wow, wow, wow.
Oh, my god, you motherfucker!
Hey, a bunch of bombs.
A chariot.
You know what?
Why not?
I'll use that for a bit.
Uh,
right, okay.
That was fun.
Give me my card again.
Better than letting it rot, right?
This is like the most useless machines ever.
Like, almost never do I want to sacrifice my HP for gold.
Like, never.
It is so rare that I want to do that.
I got a crybaby over here.
Nice.
Oh, that's mine.
I got seven bombs.
I could just willy-nilly start looking for secret rooms.
We're blowing this up.
Oh, yeah.
That's all they're good for.
Uh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, check this out, check this out.
I'm gonna move this over here and blow it up.
Damn, unlucky, but it was worth a try.
Okay.
Uh-oh.
Nice.
That was very well handled.
Okay.
You know what?
I'm gonna use this here.
This is gonna be a troublesome room.
Nice.
Beautiful.
The bra temporarily petrifies.
Um,
is that worth it?
Yes, mother, one out of three.
Man, the damage up is quite significant, though.
Wait, wait, wait, did you see my demon meter?
I lo- oh, oh, wait a second now.
I lose demon when I pick up the bra.
Oh, I guess it makes sense that I gain demon by having the book of Belial.
Because that's demonic as shit.
Aha, okay, so I'm starting to maybe understand what's going on there.
I don't really have much money here.
Here's what I'm gonna do.
We're donating everything to charity.
Ah!
Fuck, it's not a donation!
Oh well.
It happens.
God damn it.
The one time you want to be a good human and donate to charity.
You get fucked in the ass.
It's lovely.
Uh-oh.
How am I gonna do this?
Boop!
That was close.
Yeah, that's right!
Fall into the fire!
That's good.
Very good.
Hey!
Join me.
Okay.
Oh, he wants bombs.
Uh, no.
I think not.
I miss the room.
Doof!
Uh, should I be standing here?
Oh my god, that was close.
Good.
Very smooth.
Hell yeah.
I'm playing it safe this time.
Oh wait, I missed another room.
Ah, I don't want to go back up there.
Fuck that.
I've got a lot of bombs.
I could start looking for secrets now.
Yeah!
Huh?
Oh wait, I'm gonna come back and grab this after the bus.
That's the smart play.
Oh yeah.
I also have the sun.
The sun is waiting.
In case I need it.
Whoa, how did I not get hit?
Insanity.
Me, baby!
Yeah, we're going going here.
Whoa, that's a new one.
Spider.
Oh, this is my spiders.
Okay.
More spiders.
Huh?
Cursed eye.
Charge shot that fires up to five tears and a burst.
Taking damage mid-charge.
Teleports up.
Oh.
Uh, I don't like that very much.
That sucks ass.
How do I get rid of it?
This is bad.
I hate it.
Boo.
Fuck you, demon.
I hate that.
Uh, we're gonna go grab this and then we're gonna leave.
Yoink.
It's mine.
Let's let go.
Imagine getting buried alive, not being able to breathe in a box.
That's fucked up.
Now, I want you to imagine what it would have been like if you were born blind.
Wow.
How did that not hit him?
Okay, the drive-bys are pretty good.
Okay, I'm liking this.
I'm liking this.
I I jumped the gun a little bit on it.
It's actually pretty cool.
Me likey.
Me likey muchu muchu macho.
Oh, hey.
Very good.
It's like a shotgun.
Let's go this way.
And the fact that I can pre-charge before I go into a room is massive.
Just like Azazel.
Hey, hey.
All right.
Check this out.
Make a bomb, make a bomb.
Boink.
Oh, I was trying to push it to the other side.
Uh, Mr. Boom spawns a large bomb.
Why not?
Oh, I thought it would just be like a bomb I could pick up, I guess, but okay.
Flies.
All right.
Pretty cool, I guess.
Moving on.
I like the shotty.
Mom.
Uh, I have plenty of keys.
Very good.
I hit him through the rock.
Oh, fuck.
Hate these fucking enemies.
Oh my god, what a room is this?
Jesus Christ.
Holy guacafucka moly.
That is a crazy room.
Holy sh- At least I'm getting hugely rewarded with the with the hearts.
That's something.
Uh-huh.
Challenge time.
Stay mad, bro.
I love the drive-by.
Oh my god, there's so many small flies.
Oh yeah, they're gone.
Nice.
Beautiful.
Oh, oh.
Oh yeah, right.
That was a thing.
Oh my god.
I forgot that was a thing.
But that's cool.
I can dig it.
I'm scared of the fire.
Ah, leave me alone.
That works.
Finally we get this room.
Uh, Leo, Isaac and break most- Yeah, that's a good one.
We like that one.
Oh, wow.
That one was hiding a chest.
That's crazy.
We're also rich.
Um, jar of flies.
That's a blue fly to the jar for each enemy kill.
Maximum of 20 flies can be stored.
Hmm, I guess that could be pretty good, but I want to keep my book.
So, no.
Maximum donation time.
Store upgrade level three!
That sounds huge.
Yeah.
Oh, we got 20 bombs.
It's time to blow shit up.
Um, okay.
We gained a bit of demon and a bit of angel.
Maybe both angel people and demon people, they do not like the concept of a shop.
Ah!
Oh, right.
Uh, hmm.
That's fine.
Oh, God.
Ah!
Okay, that's fine.
We're gonna go back.
It's no big deal.
No big deal.
Oh, God.
Kill him, kill him.
Man, that's actually kind of huge.
Thank you.
Oh, God.
Okay, okay.
Oh, wait, I can eat rocks.
Can I eat these things?
No, too bad.
Uh, let me actually bomb this.
I feel like with this amount of bombs, we should just start bombing shit, you know?
Maybe even here.
Oh, my God!
You can do... there's stuff in these!
It's amazing.
Huge.
Uh, I think I want to keep the sun instead.
That one is even better.
Uh, yeah.
Oh, God.
I doubt I can eat the fires.
Good.
Oh, yeah, I can eat them.
Another sun!
Whoa.
I mean, I'm gonna be ready for that boss.
Oh, let me eat the rocks.
Maybe there's like a chest, you know?
I'm also gonna go in this room, because we got healing scattered.
Oh, my God.
I should not have picked that up just now.
Mistake.
That was too greedy.
Fuck!
Oh, money.
Wait, we're inside the room!
Cool.
Is this the room we couldn't access?
I'm not sure what's happening right now.
Uh, we go back in here.
Brother!
Let me get in there!
Thank you.
Oh, my God.
That's what I came here for.
Never mind.
It was worth it.
I'm gonna blow you up as well.
All right, spiders.
Very good.
All right, then.
Time for the boss.
Yep.
Oh, we can eat this!
Fuck!
That was a bomb.
Don't eat the bombs, note to self.
It's a bad idea.
Oh, these ones I want to eat, though.
The shotgun is incredible.
I slept on the shotgun for approximately five seconds, and then I realized the potential.
Especially when we activate the damage up.
Yes, sir.
Ow!
Whoa, you're fast!
You shoot three rounds, it seems.
Ow, ow, ow, ow.
Uh-oh.
Just kill him!
Nice.
Torn photo!
More tears, shot speed, love it.
Very good.
And I'm done here, right?
Oops.
Look at that clean ass map.
That is beautiful.
Absolutely wonderful.
Oh, wait a sec.
Oh my god, you don't have to charge all the way up.
The more you charge, the more shots you shoot if I just...
It's gradual.
Oh, that's cool.
I didn't know that.
Very nice.
All right, this is the mom floor.
Keep it in mind.
Mom, mom, mom, mom, mom.
Don't forget.
It's time for mom.
Oh, how did I miss that one?
Eat up all the rocks.
Eat up all...
Oh, I realized a millisecond too late.
Oh god.
I'm in trouble.
Jesus.
I'm okay.
Stand still, motherfucker!
Give me something good.
What's that?
A big fan.
Fat protector.
Orbital fly familiar that blocks enemy shots and deals contact.
Orbit slowly and slows the speed of other orbital familiars.
Okay.
That's weird.
But I guess I like it.
Oh, the laser was very unexpected.
How am I going to damage these guys?
Oh, they just take damage.
Wait, did they just extract money from me?
Hit something.
I got to find some HP or I use the sun.
Let's use it in a room that's difficult.
Maybe this one.
Oh my...
The shotgun is not suited for these types of enemies.
Let me tell you.
Uh oh.
Wait, this room sucks.
I'm not going to go in there.
Okay, one of them has laser.
We're chilling.
I saw the secret.
Consume it all.
Eat all the poop!
We got an arcade as well.
I have a little bit of money.
Oh, wait, these guys are not taking damage.
Nice.
Oh!
Looky, looky here.
Wait, what?
Someone's invisible.
Huh?
Whoa, wait, wait, wait.
What's happening?
The ladder?
Where am I right now?
Oh, this one is good.
I need the champion belt.
It cost a heart.
I don't know what that is.
I don't know what this is.
I kind of want to get it all.
I like this one.
More sacs.
Sac has.
Coins have a 10% chance to be converted to a sac?
Other pickups have a 20% chance?
But what is a sac?
Oh, oh, that's a sac!
Give me this one.
Diplopia.
It's an active.
Duplicates all pickups and item pedestals in the room.
Well, that was not good.
I should have taken that earlier, I guess.
Well, I couldn't have known.
Are these guys enemies?
I got 20 bombs.
I'm gonna blow the shit out of this place.
You want coins?
You want keys, huh?
Too bad.
You ain't getting neither.
Oh my god!
Bible tracked!
3% increased chance of finding eternal hearts.
That's a trinket, right?
Yeah.
Better than nothing.
Let's blow this guy up.
Also, let's check if there's a secret here.
No.
Give me this back.
Fuck.
Yeah.
Uh, so hold on a minute.
I can skip mom here?
I don't think I want to.
Because she's gonna drop items for me.
How cool is this, though?
How cool is that?
I keep finding new things all the time.
I also have money for the arcade.
Oh, uh...
You want health?
I'm not gonna give you that.
I'm gonna gamble a little bit.
Ah, we're not that lucky.
So maybe the play is, if you don't have a lot of luck, you just enjoy this.
Yeah, that's not good.
There we go!
Wonderful.
There's also a secret here.
Oh my goodness.
Very nice.
Man, I love, uh, eating rocks.
Oh wait, there's actually something down here, too.
But I can enter that via the other room.
Let's not overdo it.
Here.
Maximum damage.
How on earth?
Wow, what a room.
Oh god.
Oh my fucking god.
Who?
What is this room?
Oh, a challenge room.
I didn't get to read who I was fighting.
Here, you like bombs?
That's for you.
Oh my god.
Get out of the way.
Nice.
Oh, this thing.
Uh, I don't like that at all.
I hate that item.
Like red chests, they're not good in my experience.
The only good thing is they don't require a key.
Okay, okay, I got a little scared there.
I can probably not eat the spiky rocks.
I'm not gonna test that.
No way.
What I will do is destroy this.
Just so I have an easier axis.
No risks.
Thanks.
Actually...
Oh, timer went off.
I'm gonna take a break in just a second here.
I just gotta get this one.
I think I can actually get this without destroying it.
Oh yeah, it's not that bad.
Special door opened!
Ooh, that was close!
All right, guys.
Five minute break.
We're back.
I want to regale you with a story.
It's a great one.
I was in the fridge.
Inside the fridge.
And I took out a one square centimeter of chocolate.
Dark chocolate.
Because apparently that's also good for you.
And I ate it.
And you know what?
I'm feeling extremely full.
Right now, after eating that little square centimeter.
How is this possible?
Like, I'm feeling bloated from that.
That's wild.
That's my story.
That's about it.
See ya.
Oh yeah, right.
That's the thing.
Uh oh.
Vomit!
Pro.
It's empty?
I have literally never seen that before.
This is why the red chests suck.
They are literally empty.
That is disgusting.
Also, I'm almost dead here.
I think I played with the devil a little too much when I sacrificed all my hearts.
This is not gonna go well for me.
Okay, that's good.
Very nice.
A little bomb.
Oh my god.
Get away from me.
Ah!
Okay.
Please let there be some health in this sack.
No health.
Damn.
We do have some health back here though.
I should go get that.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
That was scary.
Fill up on HP.
There we go.
And let's go to the shop, because I am rich.
This one's probably not good, right?
Ooh, discounted pill.
Fantastic.
I love it.
Donate all my money to charity, because I'm about to die.
Actually, use the last seven on this.
All right, some bombs.
That's pretty decent.
May as well blow everything up before I leave this Earth, right?
Some more money.
This goes in here, I guess.
There you go.
We lost demon mode, because we donated?
Huh.
I'm gonna blow you up as well.
Oh, careful not to touch him.
Nah.
Oh.
I'm gonna move my mouse pad a little out of the way, because it's actually quite annoying to have next to me when I'm using only the keyboard.
My arm is sort of overlapping on the mouse pad and the hardwood table, you know?
Not a good combo.
Okay, it's time for the boss with one HP.
Wish me luck.
Oh, it's mama's.
Oh, we're dead.
We're so dead.
There's no way we're not dead.
Oh my god.
Yeah, there it is.
Rip.
That's how that goes.
You know what?
Should we play with Isaac a bit?
Who else did we unlock?
Judas, Eve...
Samson was pretty dang cool.
I feel like I should try Samson again.
Or Eden.
I don't know what this Eden tokens is.
So right now we have two Eden tokens.
Let's play with Eden and see what happens to the tokens.
Okay, so wait.
We got items.
Head of Krampus.
Fires a Brimstone laser attack in all four cardinal directions.
That's active.
Nancy bombs.
Plus five bombs.
Bombs gain one to four random bomb enhancing effects.
Okay.
Nice haircut.
Oh my goodness.
Yeah, I'm just gonna avoid that, I guess.
I got no money.
I literally died last run to pills.
Pills were my downfall.
I got addicted bad.
And I died from an overdose.
True facts.
My attack speed is horrendous.
Okay.
Boink!
That's amazing.
I'm trying to look for tinted rocks as well.
Am I seeing any in this big of a room with this many rocks?
Come on, there's got to be one.
Okay, maybe not.
Imagine being the guy that eats rocks in here.
Leo.
What's the name?
Are you good?
Where are they?
These enemies suck so much.
Ah, come on.
There we go.
Um...
Yeah.
Actually, wait, we're gonna do this.
Whoa!
Did you see that?
That was hella cool.
Random bomb effects.
We're not gonna go in yet, because we don't have the item.
The treasure.
The treasure is quite important.
Let's go this way.
We got the rainbow poop again.
I still have no idea what it does.
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow.
Nice.
Okay, what is this?
Let me try and pay attention.
No stat changes, no nothing.
Maybe it's like a...
Maybe it changes the type of items that can spawn later to have more colors or something.
You know?
Because all the colors are usually related to having different effects on your tier.
So maybe that increases chance of finding items that give me that sort of effect, you know?
Sulfuric acid.
Acid tears!
Would you look at that?
More damage?
Chance to fire acid tears that destroy rocks?
And most breakable objects on impact?
Whoa!
That sounds amazing.
I think that's what the poop does, the rainbow poop.
Kill this guy.
Look at that!
That's incredible.
Now the question is, does this explode on acid?
It does!
Oh, okay, okay.
Yeah, just go.
You can't reach me.
So the question is, should I just be standing here destroying rocks technically?
Because there could be a chest inside.
That sounds tedious as hell.
Nah, no way I'm doing that.
But I could destroy this guy because there's a bomb.
Yeah, nothing though.
I didn't think they would come in there!
Fuck!
That just made me scared.
Thought I was safe!
False sense of security.
Okay, we grab the heart and we engage the boss.
Yeah, we also have the brimstone effect on active.
Oh my god, it's so good!
Insanity.
I'm gonna jump.
Please don't die now.
That would make things very sad.
A booster pack.
I mean, that can be good.
The side is amazing.
Doubles, Isaac's coins.
I don't have any.
Doubles, keys.
Slot machine.
Wait.
Sponsored slot machine, 74%.
Fortune teller, 25%.
Or a crane game?
Dude!
Damn, I wanted the crane game.
Hey, okay.
Uh, plus two damage for the room.
I'm gonna blow this up.
Cluster bomb or something.
Okay, uh, I might as well use this.
May as well use this one down here as...
No, wait, where's the other one?
Yeah, just double coins now, I guess.
It's a waste, but not really much else I can do.
Okay, moving on.
So I'm playing as Eden right now.
And I have two Eden tokens.
I do wonder what that means.
I'm not gonna forget.
We're gonna check the tokens after this and see if it changed.
Ha!
I broke a pot!
You're kidding me!
Fucking hell.
Why not?
I was scared of going into that poison.
Come on.
Ah, too bad.
Oh, my...
It's over.
GG.
I sort of just left...
I just lifted my hands off the keyboard when I was in the corner.
I was like, fuck this, it's over.
Uh, let's go with Lilith.
Lilith, Incubus.
Oh, wait, Champion...
Campion Conception.
This is the one that's...
This is the one that shoots from Familius, right?
I don't want to get one Eden token.
We're doing it again.
Let's see what happens when we reach zero.
Nice haircut.
Mom's box spawns a trinket.
Doubles the effects of trinkets.
Oh, Virgo.
Chance when taking damage to activate a shield increases with luck.
Oh, we have 1.68 luck.
What a weird amount.
Converge negative pill effects.
It's a positive one!
I love that one!
We're gonna be pilling it up hard!
Yes!
Whipworm!
All right!
Cool!
Very neat.
Oh my god.
Dude, they're so fast!
That is cool as hell!
Yeah.
I love the shot speed.
Oh, that's actually so weird.
I feel like I never have this high shot speed.
This is so weird.
Not used to that.
Rainbow, baby!
Familius that fires tears with many rent.
Look!
You see what I mean with the rainbow?
Man, you randomized effects from other familius.
Yeah, I'm totally right.
Thanks.
With this high shot speed, that should be interesting.
Let's just kill these guys.
Money room?
Yeah, okay.
I guess I can do that.
This one is on sale.
And I was holding two active items at once.
When holding two active items, press the swap button to switch between them.
So wait, this is not an active item in itself.
This is just like an item.
Yeah, okay.
So we're gonna get another active item and we're gonna...
Is it control or what?
I think it's control.
I'm gonna save my money.
Very intriguing so far.
Also, I should be using mom's box here.
Just to see what I get from trinkets.
Hookworm!
More tiers, more range.
Tears travel in a larger square wave.
Ahhh!
No.
Nope.
I don't like that.
Oh, wait a minute.
Okay, I thought for a second it meant two active trinkets, but it's two active items, okay.
I think they should change the sound these guys make when they die.
Because it sounds 100% like I'm taking damage.
It is super confusing.
It's messing with my brain.
Increase chance of finding red hearts.
66% chance to add an additional red heart.
Red hearts are not that good.
Like, it's just healing.
Beautiful.
Check for rocks.
Oh, we got a rock!
Holy shit!
Oh, wait, this is not the one where we can acid, is it?
That was last time?
Yeah.
So we're gonna bomb it.
We got no bombs!
Ah, fuck, okay, we'll come back, I guess.
Too bad.
No, there's nothing else!
Uh-oh.
There is this room up here, but...
Yeah.
Oh, man, that's a bummer.
Actually, let me try this real quick.
You know?
That is actually kind of cool.
That is really weird.
Do I like that more?
I think I do.
Dude, we're gonna run with this.
Oh, wait, wrong way.
Let's try it out!
It's the garglings.
Oh, god.
How weird is this?
I mean, shots are super slow, though.
Come here, you.
Ow!
They're so fast.
The belt, more speed, I guess I like that.
You know what?
I don't think I like this super much.
I'm gonna go back and change it back.
I just wanna have straight shots right now.
Don't overcomplicate it.
Oh, curse of darkness!
100% demon mode, though.
Wow!
Oh, he's charmed!
Sick.
That bomb, very good.
Let's look for these tinted rocks.
Not in here.
This is actually kind of a scary situation.
Uh, we can just run.
Run!
Ah!
Scary.
Oh, wait, I'm not hitting it.
Let's try this.
Safety scissors.
Diffuses troll bombs and converts them into bomb pickups!
Reduces the size of enemy explosions.
Whoa!
But I don't think that's worth it, compared to the extra shot speed I have here.
It is very cool, I will say that.
Nice.
Also, we have temperance.
What is that again?
Spawns a blood donation.
Okay.
Hey, he's charmed!
Nice!
No tinted rocks.
Crack the sky.
Summon five beams.
Oh...
I mean, I can have two, right?
Okay, so it is controlled.
Oh, that's super cool!
I wonder if they get charged at the same time, or only the one I have active right now.
Let's try it.
Okay, so notice how it's at one.
The other one is at two.
We're gonna leave it like this and see what happens.
Uh, we don't have any money, so may as well not go in there.
Not yet.
Nice.
Pills.
Wait a minute, all pills are good, right?
Converts negative pill effects into positive ones!
Beautiful.
Oh, so wait, it looks like it's charging Mom's box first?
Oh my god, there's so many enemies here.
It may actually be over!
Oh...
Wow.
It's so dark here.
Uh, okay, okay.
Let me try this.
Giganta Bean.
The size of Isaac's Farts has increased.
All Farts gain significantly.
That's useless.
Absolutely useless.
Any tinted rocks?
No.
Hey!
That was good!
Uh, right.
I was gonna try and see what Temperance was, but I know what it is.
Yeah, get charmed.
Get charmed.
We like that.
And healing is fantastic.
Uh, right.
I'm gonna get more healing before I engage that boss, I think.
We have to.
Go up here.
Let's check out this room.
This room looks funny.
There's an X.
Okay, well, I think it's time.
I'm gonna have a quick gander at the shop.
With all...
Ooh.
Ooh, we also have this one.
But I think I'm gonna buy that Heart.
Much needed.
See ya later.
Now we go for the boss.
Oh wait, you know what we could do?
We're gonna come back for that later.
Very nice.
Let's do this.
It's the Heart.
Wait, there was only one?
Huh?
Normally he has like three.
Oh my fucking god.
Wait, he's dead already?
What just happened?
Stapler?
I still don't understand the system with the left and right eye.
It is such an obscure thing for me.
Little brimstone is pretty good.
A little horn.
Chance to fire void, tears to summon Bighorn's hand.
That is also good.
Chance increases with luck.
I have pretty good luck.
Bighorn's hand instantly kills.
Normally, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, I think I like that one actually.
This is a decision here.
Yeah, little brimstone is not that good.
I like this way more.
Yeah, and then we're gonna go back and grab the Eternal Heart.
It shall last forever.
And then it actually means that we got this item for free now.
If you think about it.
Which is not too shabby.
Okay, going in.
Things are looking pretty good.
We got 33% demon mode for whatever reason.
Nobody knows.
Poops!
Yo, I love the fiery thingies we're shooting.
The rainbow effect.
Mom's pet.
Oh, let me see what this produces first.
Little larva.
Destroyed poop spawn two blue attack flies.
Nah.
I like this one.
Yeah, I like that.
I could go in here, but only on one side.
I got two bombs only.
Let's see what we got.
Blueheart, I could buy that if I get the two coins in there.
Could be worth it.
I'll come back.
Let's see what happens if we find some money.
I'm gonna try mom's pet.
Not here, though.
That would be a waste.
Wait, is that a special rock right there?
Look at this!
I'm gonna hit both flies with one fly's water.
Amazing!
Get feared!
Mom's pet is here!
Wake up!
Nice.
Lasers.
Yo, imagine...
Could you have two swoop the whoops with this?
I wonder if you can have two of the same item.
That'll be cool.
Oh no, my nemesis!
Actually, I figured out the way to do it.
Oh my god, I just realized.
The surefire way to get it done every time.
E, how did I ever fuck this up so bad?
Hello?
The hand!
Did you see the hand?
Oh, I bumped my head into the microphone.
I apologize.
Not the tomatoes!
Another chest!
Oh, thank you.
Fuck!
Whoa!
Good.
Solid.
It's Peep.
I wonder if this works against Peep.
Hey, it does!
He's scared now.
Wow!
Good.
Don't get hit by that.
Nice!
Nice.
That was clean as hell.
Wait, I've never seen this before.
I feel like I've seen this a million times.
Experimental treatment.
Some stats up, some stats down.
Oh, that is fantastic!
That is a really good stat distribution we just acquired there.
Uh, we're getting out.
The only thing I lost was a bit of speed, but I think that's okay.
Let me see the speed here.
Yeah, we are kind of standards-ish.
I could get over there.
I'm gonna do it.
Totally worth.
Wow.
Let me leave!
Um...
Okay.
Oh!
That's a lot of poop.
Wow!
Five coins just like that?
Holy crap!
Again?
Dude, I'm right yourself!
Wait, I only have two hearts?
I thought I was rocking more than that.
Oh man, I wish you could re-roll here.
Too bad.
Um...
Response five random cards.
Yeah, actually, I think it's good.
Teleport to the shop.
Lot donation.
Why not?
Blow it up.
Plus two damage for the room.
Ah, man, these are all shit.
Copies the effective Isaac's active item.
That could be pretty cool, I guess.
Plus two damage.
Honestly, I don't know what's...
You know what, let's carry this around.
I feel like I want to stay on the safe side here.
Donate the rest.
Honestly, just go crazy with the donation here.
It broke, good.
Get feared.
I love the hand.
Oh, he wants coins.
We can oblige.
Hey, thanks.
Very cool.
Oh, you know what, let's blow this entire thing up.
Not bad.
I'm gonna take these rooms out now.
Wow.
Use this.
Play it safe, right?
Oh, this door's closed.
Fuck.
Oh, well, we got healed again.
I thought he would have died.
I gambled a little there.
Arcade, I'm out of money though, but I'm not out of bombs.
Oh, it cost a coin to enter.
I thought that was a key.
Okay, that's interesting.
I didn't realize.
Oh, my God, fucking shot me from beyond the grave.
Yo, man, those flies are scary.
There's the treasure room.
What is that?
Tooth and nail, you feel prickly.
Let me guess, they take damage when they hit me?
Every six seconds transform into a spiky statue form for one second.
In this statue form, Isaac is invincible to most forms of damage and deals 40 contact damage.
I mean, I'm just gonna treat that as a random RNG chance to take less damage when shit happens.
I'm not gonna...
Oh, that's gonna be annoying to listen to.
We do have some HP we can grab.
Give
me that one.
Yeah, time for the boss.
Here we go.
Carrion Queen.
I'm gonna fear.
We're gonna bomb.
That is amazing.
He's gonna poop everywhere, of course, because that is what he does.
I was trying to run into him with the spiky form.
I don't think he did anything.
Consolation prize.
Does that increase based on whichever one is the lowest?
That means speed, right?
Or luck, actually could be luck.
No, it's speed, okay.
Not bad.
Is it saying gym, gym, gym, gym?
No way.
Huh, all right.
Okay.
Very good.
Oh, we got a challenge room here.
Definitely gonna use mom's pad in here.
Wait, why are these guys so tough?
Holy shit, man, they're tough.
What's happening?
Oh, okay, I see.
Oh, wow, get padded.
Okay, I'll take one of those.
Let's go up here.
They actually dodged everything because they were jumping.
What the fuck is going on right now?
I ran into them on purpose there because I was spiked.
You can believe that or not, but I did.
Oh, oh, oh, what the fuck is following me?
I thought it was on predetermined paths.
The frick, man.
There's a crazy room.
Okay.
I'm going back to get that heart.
Yoink, I actually have so many bombs.
Let's just start bombing shit.
Nope.
What about here?
Dammit.
Interesting.
I think I'm going to blow you up, sir.
An ace of spades?
The hell is that?
10% increased chance of finding a card as a room clear reward.
Chance to add an additional card.
Nah, that's horrible.
Absolutely terrible.
I want this.
I want whoosh.
Oh, no, I don't want to go that way.
Go back.
Regrets.
Calm down.
Dude, these guys have no chill at all.
That's huge.
Well, now I have some healing if I need it later.
Oh, that was close.
Appill.
Sick.
My attack speed is getting respectable.
Very respectable.
God, my aim is terrible.
Fear them.
Jesus.
There was a panic button just now.
I need more HP.
This is the priority right now.
I need HP.
Well, this is not going to help me at all.
What if I blow up the refresh?
Oh, that refreshes.
Oh, I want the champion belt real bad.
Can we earn the money?
Oh, what the...
This is like the stuff from the foreskin boss.
Same type of enemy.
Nice.
Any tinted rocks?
I didn't mean to engage the boss.
Fuck.
It's okay, though.
Somehow it worked out.
You know what?
It's actually starting to grow on me.
The gym, gym, gym, gym.
I like it.
The Jesus juice is huge.
Love me some Jesus juice.
But we're not done.
We're going.
Oh, wait.
I didn't check whether or not we got a special room there.
Hope we didn't get one.
Now, you know what?
In any case, I wouldn't have sacrificed any hearts because I need them right now.
Oh, my God.
Fuck!
Wow.
They're still shooting?
Why?
Oh, my God.
Insanity.
I need healing.
Thanks.
I still haven't found the money that I need to buy the thing that I want in the room that I'm not going to.
Oh, God.
Beautiful.
The choke point!
That was amazing.
It was beautiful.
Get bombed, nerd.
Oh.
I have insane range.
I really should start using this to my advantage.
Number one.
More tiers, less range.
Ooh, a lot of less range.
I feel like this is not good.
Think about it.
I already have so many tiers.
I like my range.
This can go fuck itself.
I made a mature decision there, I think.
That was actually really good.
Now, to get across here, that's...
Wait, how does that work?
Can I do that?
Do I do one here?
Wait, what?
How am I supposed to...
I guess I can't.
Prick.
Jim, Jim, Jim.
This way.
You know what, let's have a look here.
We're going to start using the range a lot to our advantage.
We're going to play Space Invaders.
This is the mom floor, mom.
I still only have two hearts.
It may actually be over.
I don't think I can fight mom and survive with two hearts.
It is a sad reality, but...
How was that?
Oh, that's good!
Is it though?
Yes, it is, because I only have two hearts.
Fantastic.
This was amazing find.
Jim, Jim, Jim.
Wait, these are going to wake up and fuck me in the ass.
Is it worth it for the money, though?
Oh!
I have no healing.
Wait, dice room.
Five!
Oh, I want to check.
I want to see what that does.
What's that?
Louse.
Wait,
what happened?
I don't know what just happened.
What I think happened is I accidentally stepped on and triggered the dice.
And the five-sided dice pushed me back to the beginning of the floor, it seems.
All right.
Well, that's cool, I guess.
Rosary beat increases chance of encountering the Bible.
When a devil room would appear, an angel room appears instead.
A hundred percent angel chance right now.
We like that.
We like that a lot.
But here's what I'm going to do.
I'm going to equip this before we get to the boss.
Not yet.
Uh...
Yeah.
Okay.
Boom!
Show me the good stuff.
No good stuff.
Oh, this guy's immune to fear!
What the fuck?
Why was he immune?
He's immune to damage!
That's not fair!
Are you...
Okay, now I can damage you.
Bullshit, man.
Okay, that coin is ripped, because I can't get to that.
Oh, no!
This is my nightmare room!
Oh,
we did it!
Oh, my...
X-ray!
Yeah, baby!
We love that.
Let's see where.
Wait, I don't see shit.
I guess it's when you enter the room, then you see the shit.
Aha!
Uh-oh.
Fear!
That's right!
I thought you had feared!
What is this fucking lie?!
The fear effect was on him, and yet he shoots me?!
Bullshit!
So you can't count on the fear effect?
Good to know.
I was counting on him being unable to attack!
What the hell, man?
Mom!
I'm losing all my HPs right now.
Oh, there we go.
We got a golden farter.
I got money, baby!
Let's play some games.
Okay, that's good for later.
My lock is pretty bad.
Well, it could be worse, but...
Skatole, fly love.
Many fly enemies become less dangerous, I love that.
Because fuck those enemies.
Time to play these games.
Hey!
I love the music in this room.
Come on, man!
One more!
Portable slot!
No, I don't like that.
I'd rather have this.
We're gonna blow this up.
Ah, I could have used that money in the...
I should have thought about that.
That's okay.
Ah, let's see, we got the pad ready.
Let's use it.
So they can apparently still shoot, so I'm gonna be on the lookout.
He looks like these guys are not shooting.
Maybe champion enemies and bosses do not get affected by the non-shoot.
Hey!
My range is out of control right now.
Everyone knows it.
Use the range, use the range.
Oh, these guys are gonna jump.
Keep moving, keep moving.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, man, I'm so proud of myself.
This is some good-ass gameplay.
I'm gonna go back and grab a heart.
This is about saving one of my nine lives.
It's smart.
Wait, we have a poop on our head.
It's actually kind of a banger outfit we're rocking here.
We look like the nerdy poop goth girl, you know?
Oh my god!
Shit!
I don't like when they're shooting at me.
No!
Fuck this room!
This room is impossible.
It's actually over.
Oh, unbelievable!
This room was crazy!
Holy difficulty!
I have no money.
Huh?
Oh, nice!
You want keys?
Oh, you want keys?
I got keys for you, baby!
Here you go.
Eat them all.
Okay, don't eat all of them.
Give me something in return!
Really?
Fuck you!
Eat a piece of shit.
Go!
Kill them.
I feel like gym stuff is starting to taunt me a little bit now.
Fuck me!
All right, we're going in.
It's Mom.
I think we're done.
Why is her foot blue?
Why didn't it hit the foot?
God fucking damn it.
Huh?
I don't know what's happening.
There's no way we can do this.
I can't beat this boss.
I just don't have good enough items, man.
I can't do it.
We're going to spend all of our health on this.
And we're going to lose.
It's the sad reality.
I don't know why Mom is suddenly blue.
Like, I don't know what's going on with that either.
It's very mysterious.
What the fuck is going on?
Give me that shit.
Moving on.
Oh, cheers.
What do we got here?
Uh, nothing of interest.
Now that's interesting.
Wish I didn't spend all my keys on that piece of shit.
Cursed skull.
When damage to a half heart remaining, Isaac instantly tele- No thanks.
That sounds bad.
I got no more keys now.
Yeah, how am I supposed to dodge that?
What the fuck?
Calm down.
Stay away.
Holy shit, you have a lot of HP, man!
Oh wait, it's a boss.
Okay, that makes more sense.
I thought it was just a singular enemy.
I was losing my mind.
Give me those tears.
Damn right, my tears are up.
Aha!
That's a golden poop.
Except I doubt there's a steam sail down here in the uterus or whatever.
Uh, let's think.
Let's activate this.
No, actually, uh, we don't have a key yet.
I'll come back.
Another one of these?
What the frick?
Unidentified?
I can see forever.
Meaning secret rooms?
Here's an increased knockback.
No, I like this more still.
I really do like this.
Oh my god.
See ya.
It's pill heaven!
Nice!
Balls of steam!
Even nicer!
Even smaller?
Even smaller.
We're going tiny, tiny miniature, miniature creature.
Except now I'm going to have trouble seeing where I am.
So that's the downside of that.
Oh my god, I couldn't even see where my character was.
Uh, okay.
Wait, I don't want to do this.
Do I?
Do I want to do this?
I want to do this.
Moms, lock it.
Heal for half red heart whenever I say unlock something?
Converts, half red heart drops into a hole.
I mean, that's not going to matter too much.
No, that's probably a trinket as well.
Actually, is it?
It isn't.
Ah, damn it.
Okay, uh, let's go this way.
Yeah, the main way I'm going to see where my character is, to see where my shots are originating from.
It sounds really dumb, but it is the best way to do it.
Nice.
Equality, grants a large fire rate increase when collected.
Coins, bombs, and keys are all equal in number.
Okay.
Huh.
That sounds pretty cool.
So is it going to be more than 0.5 though?
That's the question.
Uh...
When I have a way to spend my money, I'll come back and grab it.
There's also another room I got to go back to and open chests.
That is the fight room.
That comes later.
What is this guy orbiting?
That's the boss.
That is not Mom's heart, not yet.
Who the hell are you?
You're like half a devil or something.
No problemo.
Okay.
Down here.
Don't touch that.
Oh no.
Oh, this is going to be a problem.
What am I taking damage from?
Oh, did I step on it?
Oh no!
I mean, this room is fucking crazy.
I'm not going back in there.
That is a killer of a room.
Oh, there's a room after it!
We got to go in.
Get lasered!
Oh my god.
Did I really not get hit by the spikes?
Am I too small?
Did I actually go in between those spikes?
No way.
Oh, this is...
Nope.
That is not happening.
How did I not get hit?
Was I just too small?
What the hell, man?
Wow.
Oh god.
Fear them.
Can you shoot?
You can't shoot.
Okay.
These guys are immobilized or pacified.
You serious candy!
Isaac Fartsher poops every 30 seconds.
No.
That sounds bad.
I don't want that.
Oh, we got demon poop.
Worth.
If I was smart, I would have put the bomb here, so I could have blown up these rocks and checked down here as well at the same time.
Dammit.
That was a bit risky.
Okay, let's go spend that key.
Up here.
Pill.
Tears up.
Man, being tiny in size is kind of good.
Come on.
Show yourself.
Oh no.
Clean.
Mega clean.
All right, it's time.
I got both actives ready, it's time for the boss.
And let's hope for a plus health, a reward here, because we need it.
Teratoma?
New boss?
No, never mind, I've seen this guy.
Fear every...
Oh, dude, we're gonna do this.
Oh!
That's hot.
Speedball.
Fuck.
I mean, glass cannon, just embrace it, right?
Book of Belial.
That'll be really good, actually, but I can't do it.
I can't do it.
We gotta keep these hearts, man.
I do have a bunch of money.
We could get super lucky in here and get some good stuff.
So, this floor is gonna be mom's heart.
Come on, give me something good.
I mean, okay.
Blue hearts, please, or black hearts.
Or eternal hearts.
Thanks!
I didn't mean to actually pick it up, it just fell into my lap.
But actually, we're not gonna save it anyway, right?
So, this is the last floor.
Oh!
Well, rip.
You know what, blow him up.
Oh, wait, he's gonna... yeah.
I didn't think about that.
Well, okay, that was a fun arcade.
Moving on.
Wait, who are you?
Or a sack, is what they're called.
Wait, I can't tell... oh, it's a pill.
Ah, I wish I could get it, but I can't.
Unfortunately.
Oh my god, I can't see my character!
Okay, there I am.
What a crazy room.
Dude,
that is... look at this shit on the floor!
That is so badly designed, that needs to be more clear.
Are you kidding me?
Like, you can barely fucking see it.
And with all the other crap on the screen.
Gimme something good!
Blue hearts, black hearts, can I even get that from these?
In any case, I'm gonna spend all my money.
Ah, okay, fine.
Okay.
Gym, gym, gym.
Oh my god!
Wow.
Oh, we got more money.
Hey!
Wait, uh, the hairpin has appeared.
Sweet.
I like unlocking more things.
More things to unlock, please.
How the fuck are you supposed to dodge that?
Hello?
By doing this, perhaps.
Uh-oh.
Oh my...
Gaaah!
Wow.
Yeah, that's not happening, unfortunately.
Wait, am I small enough to walk in between?
Hold on.
It works like that!
Oh, I'm maxed on tears or something.
What the fuck?
Dude, the small size has other effects that are good.
That is really nice.
Wow.
Okay.
Uh, you're up here now.
Uh-oh.
Wow, the hand really did a number on him.
Danke schön?
Hopefully.
That's my last life.
How the heck am I gonna...
Oh, right, they go down, okay.
This is looking pretty bad.
Fucking gravity is preventing me from shooting this guy.
Wow.
Oh no, fuck no!
I think this is where the journey ends.
Brrrrrap!
Oh!
Yeah, it's over.
I knew it was gonna end there.
I knew it.
I just knew it.
Well, guys, it's, uh, almost six o'clock.
I wish I could keep playing, I really do, but I gotta go.
I gotta stick to my schedule here.
That was a good run, though.
All things considered.
I would say that was a success.
That was a success.
Didn't get any win, though.
That feels bad.
But, you know...
By the way, yeah, the gym, gym, gym stuff.
That wasn't added with the button mod, right?
That's just part of the game.
It sounds exactly like gym, gym, gym.
Because it sounds like gym.
It's because that item uses the button sound rep...
Oh, is it actually the mod?!
That's even better!
Wait, hold on.
What is the original sound?
What does it actually say, then?
Oh, I guess it makes the sound of the button, then.
The one that goes...
Yeah, okay, okay.
Dude, I love that.
And I guess the gym sound, as well, has been sort of pitch changed.
Automatically by the game.
Because I guess the pitch may be a little different for that effect.
Yeah, exactly.
That is so hilarious.
We're gonna keep it.
I wonder what else we're gonna find.
That is also affected with the gym.
Right?
Like, I actually...
I wasn't sure whether or not that was intended or if I was just imagining the gym in my mind.
What were you guys' reaction to that?
Did you know that that was gonna happen?
Frank, when you made the mod, did you realize that it had that effect?
Or what?
You didn't?
That's even better!
Oh, yes.
Yes.
That is hilarious.
I just thought it was the sound of it.
I didn't realize at first it was gym.
Then after a while, I was like, wait a minute.
This sounds like gym.
It's incredible.
I think we have to make it a thing in every game I play, if we can.
Mod in some kind of gym sound.
It's the one red thread across all streams.
Right?
Yeah, we've got to discover all the gyms.
We've got to collect them all.
This is actually so funny.
The gym multiverse.
Uncut gyms!
I love that third sharrow!
Good one.
Dude, you should call the mod that.
Uncut gyms.
That's actually such a good movie, by the way.
You should watch Uncut Gyms.
It's with Adam Sandler.
He's amazing in it.
Oh yeah, you're right, Rob Elf.
The challenges.
Next time I'm going to do some of those.
I actually kind of forgot about them this time.
I do want to do more of them, because I thought the short stint I had in the challenge with the solar system was really fun, actually.
It was kind of weird, but it was fun.
I want to see what else there is.
I've not seen Marty Supreme.
Same director.
Ooh, then I'm intrigued.
Because that was a masterfully directed movie.
Uncut gyms, that is.
Favorite character besides the sasle?
Oh, it's gotta be...
I really like...
I think it's Eden.
The guy that has two random items.
I think it's really fun to see what items I get.
Least favorite is probably Judas.
Just because you start with 1 HP and I'm not good at the game yet.
So it's just a recipe for dying early, you know?
Yeah, I know about that, Elmecha.
Maybe I'll install that soon.
But I feel like we're going to wait a bit more until then.
What did you think of Eulith?
I actually don't remember exactly what Eulith is.
I think that was the one with the familiars.
I think the one with familiars could be really fun, depending on what you find in terms of items.
And it can be really bad, depending on what you find with items.
But I guess you can say that about almost every character.
But especially so with Eulith.
Or Lilith, whatever.
Dude, why is it so hard for me to remember Lilith?
But you also called her Eulith just now, so...
Yeah.
I mean, I almost did a basic Isaac run today, France.
I wanted to, but then I got distracted and decided not to do it.
But yeah, I'm going to do more Isaac runs as well.
I mean, I think it's just a solid character, you know?
All around stats you start with.
It's good.
Your way's better, is it?
You like Eulith more?
I feel like Eulith is a name that I would expect more from this game than Lilith.
Trinkets are also called BLIs now.
Bottom left items, yeah.
I've not played Spore, Yuki-stan.
Isn't it a kind of game where you create your own creatures or something?
I'm not sure that's something I would enjoy.
I don't know, it sounds weird.
Doesn't sound like my type of game.
But I could be wrong.
Maybe it's exactly my type of game.
There's a mod for visibility on the creep, but why?
The fact that people had to make a mod means that the game is not designed well in that regard.
It's obviously a pro...
What about people that are actually colorblind?
Good luck to those seeing the difference there.
You know?
Like, what the hell, man?
What about people that actually have reduced the vision?
It's pretty much impossible to see that, if you're one of those people.
It's only bad in the womb.
Yeah, but if you can't get through the womb, then you can't complete the game.
Right?
I'm colorblind, I have more problems with red poop.
Oh, I guess you just run in and destroy all the poop prematurely, just to check.
Or make sure.
Is the game telling you to play Azazel?
Oh, the draw of Azazel.
I shall resist.
But, you know what, maybe we should make it a thing to always start with Azazel.
Just to, you know, rev up the engine, so to speak.
Every time I play Azazel, I actually have such a blast.
I gotta admit that.
Like, it is just such a blast to play with Azazel.
It's insane.
He's so much fun.
I love the flying, I love the laser.
So good.
But there are some characters that you can only unlock if you do something very specific.
There is one thing that I need to do with Lazarus.
I think it's to complete it without respawning once, right?
Stuff like that, that stuff I want to do, of course.
Yeah.
Anyway, I gotta go now.
Thank you so much for watching.
I'm so proud of myself for actually dying on time.
So it's exactly three hours, or a little over three hours, but yeah.
Thanks for watching.
This was a banger.
Even though we didn't get a win, it's okay.
Lots of stuff learned.
And I'm getting better.
I'll see you next time.
Bye-bye.